

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER FELLOW

🛘 🕻 (+33) 625370093 | 🔀 arthur.ouaknine@gmail.com | 🏕 arthurouaknine.github.io/ | 🛅 arthur-ouaknine | 💆 @ArthurOuaknine

# Summary\_

I am a postdoctoral researcher fellow at McGill University and Mila (Quebec Artificial Intelligence Institute), in collaboration with David Rolnick. My research projects are focused on multimodal and multitask deep learning applied to forest monitoring. I'm also a core team member of Climate Change AI leading the webinar team.

I completed my Ph.D. in March 2022 in collaboration between Institut Polytechnique de Paris (Telecom Paris; Image, Data and Signal department) and Valeo.ai (international research center in artificial intelligence applied to autonomous driving). The aim of my work was to use and adapt deep neural network architectures for scene understanding using automotive radar data and multi-sensor fusion.

# **Experience**

Climate Change AI Remote

CORE TEAM MEMBER Feb 2023 - Now

- · Lead the webinars team.
- Volunteer in a non-profit organisation related to climate change and artificial intelligence.

#### McGill University and Mila Montreal, Quebec, Canada

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER FELLOW

Sep 2022 - Now

- · Deep learning architectures for multimodal and multitask learning.
- Forest monitoring using deep learning algorithms.
- Managing research projects of PhD students at Mila.

Valeo.ai Paris, France

PH.D. STUDENT IN DEEP LEARNING

Jan 2019 - Mar 2022

- Creation of CARRADA open source dataset for scene understanding application with camera and radar data. Annotations are generated on
  radar representations using a semi-supervised algorithm based on natural images. Code and data are available at https://github.com/
  valeoai/carrada dataset.
- Creation of deep neural network architectures with their associated loss functions for multi-view radar semantic segmentation. Code and
  pre-trained models are available at https://github.com/valeoai/MVRSS.
- Creation of a deep neural network architecture for HD radar preprocessing estimation and multi-task learning.
- Preliminary work on multi-sensor fusion for self-supervised learning.
- Accepted articles at ICPR 2020, ICCV 2021 and CVPR 2022. See publications section for further details.
- Assistant Professor in computer vision and machine learning. Co-supervisor of student projects (1 to 4 students): radar semantic segmentation, SAR image denoising, iceberg segmentation and tracking, deforestation detection (optical and SAR images). Details are available here.
- Co-organizer of the Deep Learning Working Group of the IMAGES team at Telecom Paris.

Valeo.ai Paris, France

RESEARCH ENGINEER Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

- Discussions between Valeo and Telecom team members about radar theory and data.
- Creation of a radar simulator for data generation.
- · Classification of the simulated data using deep learning.

Faircast Paris, France

RESEARCH ENGINEER (FREELANCE)

Jun 2018

3D point cloud segmentation using Superpoint Graph (L. Landrieu and M. Simonovsky, CVPR 2018) on LiDAR data for object removal in parisian
apartment.

**Zyl** Saint-Maur-des-Fossés, France

COMPUTER VISION ENGINEER

Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

- · Application of deep learning methods for computer vision (object detection) embedded on smartphone (compression).
- Deep Learning modelling for Visual Sentiment Analysis (D. Borth et al., ACM 2013) and transfer learning.
- State-of-the-Art review of deep learning applied to image classification, object detection and model compression.

**Idemia** Paris, France

DATA SCIENCE PROJECT

Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

- Facial keypoint detection using deep neural networks with a few number of labelled data.
- Active learning process with uncertainty quantification for training optimization using Monte Carlo Dropout (Y. Gal and Z. Ghahramani, ICML 2016)

APRIL 30, 2023 ARTHUR OUAKNINE · RÉSUMÉ 1

Rexel Paris, France

DATA SCIENTIST Apr 2016 - Sep 2016

- · Machine learning modelling for client targeting (churn probability prediction, elasticity estimation, commercial visit optimisation)
- Text mining analysis to target clients discontent.
- · Machine learning for attrition prediction: churn probability prediction covering a large part of sale revenues, churn cause analysis.

Enedis Paris, France

Data Analyst Apr 2016 - Sep 2016

Text mining analysis, database structuring and predictive modelling.

# **Education**

## Institut Polytechnique de Paris - Telecom Paris

Palaiseau, France

**PH.D. IN DEEP LEARNING** 2019 - 2022

- Under the supervision of P. Pérez (valeo.ai), F. Tupin (Telecom Paris) and A. Newson (Telecom Paris).
- · Subject: "Scene understanding using deep learning algorithms applied to radar data for autonomous driving".
- · Accepted articles at ICPR 2020, ICCV 2021 and CVPR 2022. See publications section for further details.
- · Keywords: deep learning algorithms, signal processing, computer vision, Range-Angle-Doppler representation, semantic segmentation.

Telecom Paris Palaiseau, France

POST M.Sc. Machine Learning (with Highest Honors)

2017- 2018

- · Keywords: Machine Learning, Big Data and Distributed Systems (Spark, Hadoop).
- Data Science Project: "Active learning for facial keypoint detection using deep learning".

#### **Paris Pantheon-Sorbonne University**

*Paris, France* 2014 - 2016

M.Sc. Statistical Modelling (with Honors)

Paris Diderot University

B.S. APPLIED MATHEMATICS

2011 - 2014

## **Publications**

#### **Thesis**

• A. Ouaknine, Deep Learning for Radar Data Exploitation of Autonomous Vehicle, 2022.

## Conferences

- J. Rebut, A. Ouaknine, W. Malik and P. Pérez, Raw High-Definition Radar for Multi-Task Learning, CVPR 2022.
- A. Ouaknine, A. Newson, P. Pérez, F. Tupin and J. Rebut, Multi-View Radar Semantic Segmentation, ICCV 2021.
- A. Ouaknine, A. Newson, J. Rebut, F. Tupin and P. Pérez, CARRADA: Camera and Automotive Radar Dataset with Semi-Automatic Range-Angle-Doppler Annotations. ICPR 2020.

#### **Blog Posts**

- A. Ouaknine, Review of Deep Learning Algorithms for Image Semantic Segmentation, Medium, December 2018.
- A. Ouaknine, Deep Learning Model Compression for Image Analysis: Methods and Architectures, Medium, March 2018.
- A. Ouaknine, Review of Deep Learning Algorithms for Object Detection, Medium, February 2018.
- A. Ouaknine, Review of Deep Learning Algorithms for Image Classification, Medium, January 2018.

# Skills

### Languages

FRENCH (NATIVE), ENGLISH (FLUENT)

#### **Software Languages**

Python, Java, R, Javascript, SQL, NoSQL, C++, Scala, VBA

#### **Frameworks**

DEEP LEARNING: PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT: LINUX, DOCKER, GITHUB, CIRCLECI, SPHINX

# Interests \_\_

#### Conferences

REVIEWER IN MACHINE LEARNING CONFERENCES (CVPR, NEURIPS, ICML, ICRA).

## **Sports**

Running (10 Km, half-marathon, marathon), Bouldering, Hiking, English Boxing.

## **Travels**

Western and Eastern Europe, Canada, USA, Guatemala, Argentina, Bolivia, Colombia, Peru, Marocco, Cape Verde, Cambodia, Vietnam, Indonesia, Thailand.